Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Subhadip Maji 🔘 Featured

Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Development, Program Management, Management, Requirement Analysis, System Analysis, Coding, MVC, Javascript, jQuery, ADO. Net, ASP, Net, SDLC, HTML, CSS, Angular is, Ling, net core



Current Designation: Application Developer

Current Company: Cognizant Technologies Solutions

Current Location: Kolkata

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Kolkata, Bhubaneshwar

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Development, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement Analysis, System Analysis, Coding, Javascript, jQuery, ADO. Net, ASP, Net, HTML, CSS, ASP. Net

MVC,C#,LINQ,Entity Framework,Angularis,JQuery,JSON

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

5.7 years of professional IT experience in application development, maintenance and enhancements in ASP.net/MVC/WCF/ADO.net/Azure development.

Working with Cognizant, one of the leading IT services, business solutions and outsourcing services company, from Jan -2015 to till date.

Hands-on experience in handling production issues, Process Improvement & Incident management.

Strong skills in Development and Handling technical and functional queries. Ability to grasp quickly.

Being part of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including Requirement analysis, Design, Development, Testing, Deployment, Maintenance and Support.

Strong Interpersonal and communication skills, ability to work in a team as well as independently with minimal supervision.

Experience in representing the team in status meeting with client and delivering the team working status to onshore.

A good understanding of the fundamental business processes of any application.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Application Developer Feb 2019 to Till Date

About the Project: -

This project comes under John Hancock which mainly deals with setting insurance people, providing Medicare and Medicaid services. It?s a Broker?s site. Then we who can sell the products. There is another application where we maintain details brokers and who will be eligible for selling the Coventry products. It?s maintaining the health insurance details, online payment of bills, premiums etc.

Project Title Managed Services Client John Hancock Application Services

Role

Application Developer

Technologies

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, C#, ASP.Net, MVC,

Team Size

5

Duration

Feb 2019 to Till Date

Organization

Cognizant Technology Solutions

Infosys Limited as Application Developer

Jan 2015 to Feb 2019

Project Title Managed Services Client Aetna Healthcare

Role

Application Developer

Technologies

HTML5,CSS3,Javascript,Jquery,C#, ASP.

Team Size

22

Duration

January 2015 to Feb 2019

Organization

Infosys Ltd

Responsibilities include analyzing the issues when faced from users, and then fixing the issue which may sometimes require a code fix, fixing in code in Visual Studio, debugging the code, deploying the code and testing the application, performing the Month End Activities which takes place last Sunday of the every month.

Deployment using IIS server.

Root cause analysis of critical issues, maintaining a strong Environment Health Structure.

Involved in the support, maintenance and development of systems.

Delivering project to the client on schedule.

Carrying out design, construction, review and defect analysis activities.

Providing suitably tested fixes to defects within the sustainable delivery process.

Providing automated solutions for Manual processes with optimized design.

Analyze the root cause of the incidents and provide permanent fixes for these.

Handled the incident management calls to find out impacted applications and find the root cause to provide the solution to protect the business loss to client.

Represented the team on status call with client and onshore coordinator.

Delivered KT to the new recruits for the project.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2014

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Linux ubuntu

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
HTML5	5	2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
.NET	3.3.7	2020	5 Year(s) 7 Month(s)
JavaScript	6	2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
ccs3	3	2020	5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Angular js	2	2020	2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
JQUERY	3	2020	5 Year(s) 7 Month(s)
ASP.NET	4.5.2	2020	5 Year(s) 7 Month(s)
ADO.NET	4.5.2	2020	5 Year(s) 7 Month(s)
ASP.Net MVC	5.1.2	2020	5 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Languages Known

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=6f3e8af75651fe89dbeafff9570363415f0958004b4701400616145b0f5a5...

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Bengali	Proficient			
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: Managed Services

Client: JH Insurance

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Role: Sr. Programmer

Duration: Jul 2015 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 22

Skill Used: HTML5,CSS3,Javascript,Jquery, ASP.Net MVC, ASP.Net, C#, linq,WEB API,Angular JS

Project Details: This project comes under JH(Coventry account) which mainly deals with setting insurance plans for people, providing Medicare and Medicaid services. Its a Brokers site. Then we also have brokers who can sell the Coventry business. There is another application where we maintain details about these brokers and who will be eligible for selling the Coventry products. Its like dealing and maintaining the health insurance details, online payment of bills, premiums etc.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time